<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-02T17:01:49-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alexandre Cayla</title><subtitle>Alexandre Cayla, Product development and growth</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Purpose</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/25/On-purpose/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Purpose" /><published>2019-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/25/On-purpose</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/25/On-purpose/">&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, I’ve had the luxury of mainly focusing on projects that I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, things are never that simple (I still had bills to pay), so I taught, did some consluting work, etc. But, overall, I still had time to pursue my own projects and to try to make the most out of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This forced me to have to answer &lt;em&gt;“hard”&lt;/em&gt; questions: why was I doing what I was doing? What did I want to accomplish? I short, if I wanted to use my time meaningfully, what was my purpose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was I selling?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did I want to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I short, if I had to luxury to live meaningfully,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also did a podcast. When I spoke with people about their jobs and their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting them to open up was hard because, often, a job is… a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poeple don’t typically have autonomy or do not get the luxury of defining their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if this is something that is true for all companies. If more successful ones give more autonomy to their teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It surpised me because I think deeply about my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like working on products and on designing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;because it is my way of feeling that I am contributing to the world. Well designed products make peoples daily lives a little better. And, in a time of unrest, of diminishing social liberties, of increasing weatl inequality, this is my way of feeling that I am in control and prodiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I don’t think&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Over the past year, I’ve had the luxury of mainly focusing on projects that I wanted to do.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/social.png" /></entry></feed>