<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-17T21:36:54-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alexandre Cayla</title><subtitle>Alexandre Cayla, Product development and growth</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Fake it before you make it</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/17/Fake-it-before-you-make-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fake it before you make it" /><published>2019-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/17/Fake-it-before-you-make-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/17/Fake-it-before-you-make-it/">&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago I attended an interesting meetup that reminded me of the importance of “testing” and that “lean” is not synonymous to doing “test-driven” development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker had a very eclectic background spanning from engineering to music. She had worked at MIT, with the Red Sox and, more recently, on Project Soli at Google.  (You might have heard of it as the “Motion Sense” feature on the Google Pixel 4.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through her &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; technical talk, she spoke about building products with algorithms, motion sensors; she spoke about the challenges of getting and training data; but, she mostly stressed the importance of testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because she felt that engineers are quite prone to in love with the solution they are building, of optimizing for quality and fidelity, often at the expense of considering the value they are providing or the implications of the technology they are building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pictures/posts/redsox.png&quot; alt=&quot;Red Sox Pitcher&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in the case of the Red Sox, they were developing a system that could detect pitcher injury from motion at the joints (I am paraphrasing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they were already quite far along, they realized that because of the nature of the movement, their tech could only work with certain players (with low BMI) and that it wasn’t clear what the team should conclude from the results. To wit, should a player with an invisible micro-injury be put on the bench for 6 months? What about the impact on their career? Those were certainly not engineering questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found fascinating with her experience was that even if people designing interfaces all day felt that throwing their designs online or showing them to users was “testing”, it often wasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since she and her team were dealing with sensors and invisible interfaces, they had to be much more forthright about what they were trying to test and had to devise ways to test before actually building. As early as possible, possibly with “fake” tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pictures/posts/mechanical-turk.png&quot; alt=&quot;mechanical turk&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, with Soli, a little bit like a Mechanical Turk, they made people believe that they were interacting with motion-sensing interfaces. The participant would swipe their hands from right to left to skip songs, or move up and down to increase the volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The participants thought they were experiencing some magical tech, but the truth was that there was an intern changing the songs on Spotify as the participants were waving their hands around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why this example left an impression on me was not because it was truly novel - it wasn’t - but because it reminded me of how different “testing” can be from “lean” approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Testing” is about having a clear set of assumptions about what you are trying to validate while “lean” can often become pushing the smallest piece of software to see what sticks. Learnings come from making observations rather than “tests”. And so, they can feel much less clear-cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she said, quoting Richard Feynman, “If it [your idea] disagrees with experiment, it’s wrong”. The good thing is that if it was a test, you can progress to the next hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A couple of days ago I attended an interesting meetup that reminded me of the importance of “testing” and that “lean” is not synonymous to doing “test-driven” development.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/pictures/posts/mechanical-turk.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">On Purpose</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/25/On-purpose/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Purpose" /><published>2019-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/25/On-purpose</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/25/On-purpose/">&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, I’ve had the luxury of mainly focusing on projects that I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, things are never that simple (I still had bills to pay), so I taught, did some consulting work, etc. But, overall, I still had time to pursue my own projects and to try to make the most out of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This forced me tackle &lt;em&gt;“hard”&lt;/em&gt; questions about what I wanted to accomplish, why I chose to invest my time in certain projects rather than others… I short, if I wanted to use my time meaningfully, what was my purpose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, at the same time I was pondering these questions, I was recording episodes for a podcast project on product development, and it seemed that many people working at successful tech companies did not have a purpose. They didn’t even worry very much about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They weren’t necessarily &lt;em&gt;unhappy&lt;/em&gt;, they just didn’t have a specific reason for doing what they did. Often, it seemd that like soliders, they “fought” for their buddies in the trenches with them. Other times, it was because this was the job they enjoyed the most (or the &lt;em&gt;least bad&lt;/em&gt; one). Other times, it was because they just seemed to like building things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This outlook is also very understanderble. After all, we all have obligations to our spouses, to our kids (to the banks!) and it’s not as if we can all go on life changing journeys around the world to reconnect with our &lt;em&gt;true self&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I would have expected that people with jobs with a high degree of autonomy and creativity would have been more purposeful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-value-in-purpose&quot;&gt;The value in purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose is an interesting word as it’s related to intent. It would follow that knowing what you want to do (e.g., having a purpose) would allow you to do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, finding purpose is not required to do one’s job properly, especially when the “job” that needs to be done is defined well enough. Yet, it does have some advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to providing internal motivation for accomplishing your job and getting a sense of mastery, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/jessica-stillman/what-you-can-learn-about-career-satisfaction-from-a-hospital-janitor.html&quot;&gt;the janitors who found meaning in their work&lt;/a&gt;, purpose provides clarity of intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When intent is clear, it can be communicated, it guides action and also provides a stick by which to measure if you are achieving your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, while the world is not interested in helping you fulfill your purpose (everyone has their own concerns and will go on merrily regardless of your wants), having purpose helps you clarify your goal, even if it doesn’t tell you how you can accomplish it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, especially when offering services, with a purpose, you become your own little “lean startup” testing your offerings, tying new relationships and getting customers until you find that “product-market fit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I know that I love teaching, sharing what I know and enabling people to succeed in creating great products because, by doing so, I feel that I can make someone’s day better, even if it’s just for simple everyday tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alexandre Cayla</name></author><summary type="html">Over the past year, I’ve had the luxury of mainly focusing on projects that I wanted to do.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/social.png" /></entry></feed>